BRAVARD Amadis

- amadis.bravard[AT]outlook.com mhttps://www.amadisbravard.fr/
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/dix/ 🚃 https://www.github.com/dix/
- French/English 🌋 Lille, France

© Cloud Developer

For more than ten years, first as a Full-Stack Software Engineer then as a Technical Lead and finally as Solutions Architect, I was able to learn about various functional domains (healthcare, banking/insurance...) while working with multiple technologies (Java, Angular, Node.js, Unix...).

In order to widen my skills around the lifecycle of application software, I took a position oriented around infrastructures in the Cloud, that I now wish to validate on other missions.

If it isn't documented, it doesn't exist

Professional Experience

2022-07 to Present: Devoteam Revolve - IT Services

2022-07 to Present : Cloud Consultant AWS - Malakoff Humanis - Insurance

- Estimating, designing and developing features/fixes
- Producing, monitoring and maintaining Data oriented infrastructures on AWS
- Writing technical and functional documentation
- Support to Data Engineer on development tasks
- Support to Data Lake users

Environment

- J2EE, Angular, Python, Terraform, Git (Bitbucket), Jenkins, Grafana, Docker, AWS (EC2, RDS, S3, Lambda, Athena, EKS...), Jira, Airflow, Dataiku
- 15 people

2019-01 to 2022-06: Dedalus (ex-Inovelan) - Healthcare

2020-06 to 2022-06: Solutions Architect

- Collecting and analyzing the requirements
- Designing solutions with the international partners
- Tracking their implementation
- Making and documenting technical POC

Environment

- J2EE, Spring, Node.js, REST, HL7 FHIR, Keycloak, Apache Pulsar, Prometheus, Grafana, Docker, Unix, WSL 2
- 5 to 20 people

2019-01 to 2022-06: Technical Lead

- Implementing development industrialization practices (ticketing, documentation, process, code review...)
- Organizing brainstorms and continuous improvement practice workshops (technical, English...)
- Participating in presales, technical and functional designing workshops
- Participating in developments
- · Conducting technical interviews

Environment

- J2EE, Angular, Wildfly, Drone CI, Jira, Confluence, Visual Studio Code, Agile (Scrum), Git (Gitea)
- 5 to 20 people

2010-11 to 2018-12 : GFI Informatique - IT Services

2016-06 to 2018-12 : Technical Lead - Pacifica (Crédit Agricole) - Insurance

- · Training and monitoring the team members
- Backup project manager
- Estimating, designing and implementing features/fixes
- Writing technical and functional documentation
- Conducting technical interviews

Environment

- J2EE, AngularJS, Angular, TypeScript, RxJS, Quality Center, IntelliJ, WebStorm, Agile (Scrum), Git (GitLab)
- 5 to 20 people

2015-11 to 2016-05: Technical Analyst - Metro Cash&Carry - Retail

Designing and developing features/fixes

Environment

- PL/SQL, Bash, Java, ClearCase
- 5 people

2014-06 to 2015-11: Technical Analyst - Payline (Monext) - Web payment

- · Designing and developing features/fixes
- Connecting with partners API (PayPal, SEPA, Paylib, Skrill...)
- Quality control : PCI DSS/OWASP Top 10
- Managing development/testing environments
- Training the team members

Environment

- J2EE, Hibernate, Soap, REST, MySQL, Bash, Jenkins, Jira, Unix, CVS, Git (GitLab)
- 5 to 20 people

2012-04 to 2012-06 : Technical Analyst - France Télécom (Orange) - Automation

- Collecting and analyzing requirements of the team members
- Developing tasks automation scripts: app synchronization, development environment setup, server management

Environment

- J2EE, Spring, Visual Basic, Bash, Selenium, Jahia, Apache Tomcat, Unix, SVN
- 15 people

2011-01 to 2012-04 then 2012-06 to 2014-06: Technical Analyst - Pacifica (Crédit Agricole) - Insurance

- · Estimating, designing and developing features/fixes
- Training and monitoring the team members
- Writing technical and functional documentation

Environment

- J2EE, JavaScript, jQuery, Apache Tomcat, Mantis, Quality Center, Eclipse, SVN
- 5 to 20 people

2010-11 to 2011-01: Internship

Developing features/fixes on an internal time-tracking app

Environment

- · J2EE, Spring, GWT, Eclipse, SVN
- 3 people

Education/Training

Certifications

2023-04 : HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate (003) 2022-09 : AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

Professionals

2016-12 : Développement d'applications riches avec Angular 2 - Zénika

2016-05 : AngularJS, maîtriser le Framework JavaScript de Google - Orsys

2015-04 : OWASP, Sécurité des Applications - Advens

2009-01 to 2011-01 : D.U.T. Informatique - IUT A Lille 1



🚴 Cycling (utility, road, virtual & MTB)

📚 Personal Knowledge Management

Soap-making